nubham **Gula**t

3.8 YEARS EXPERIENCE · CONSULTANT · JAVA CLOUD BACK-END DEVELOPER

Deloitte Consulting India Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore - KA 560037, India

□ (+91) 9560073211 | shubhamqulati91@qmail.com | shubhamqulati91 | shubhamqulati91



Summary _

Consultant at Deloitte US India. 3.8 Years experience specializing in the java cloud-based backend development. Super nerd who enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Education

Jaypee Institute of Information Technology University

M.TECH COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

· Aggregate: 75%

Jaypee Institute of Information Technology University

B.Tech Computer Science and Engineering

· Aggregate: 75%

Noida, India

2013 - 2015

Noida, India

2010 - 2014

Skills_

Languages Core Java, Advanced Java

Basic - SQL, Shell, HTML, CSS, PHP, Javascript

Frameworks Micro-services, Spring, Hibernate, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Web, Spring Data

Zuul, Eureka, Hystrix, Apache POI, Okta

Other technologies Git, Gerrit, GitHub, IntelliJ IDEA, JIRA, Docker

Work Experience _____

Deloitte Consulting U.S. India

CONSULTANT

Sep. 2019 - PRESENT

Bangalore, India

- Experienced in developing distributed applications based on Micro-services Architecture.
- Experienced in developing cloud based back-end using Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Zuul and Eureka.
- Experienced in developing web APIs using Spring Web, Spring JPA, and Hibernate.
- · Experienced in working directly with client teams.
- Experienced in project time-line estimations.
- Experienced in sprint planning.

Deloitte Consulting U.S. India

BUSINESS TECHNOLOGY ANALYST

• One year development experience in Java back-end using Spring Boot, Cloud, Web and JPA.

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CGI

Two years development experience in Java back-end using Core Java, JUnit and Bash Scripting.

Bangalore, India Aug. 2016 - Apr. 2018

Bangalore, India

Apr. 2018 - Aug. 2019

SHUBHAM GULATI · RÉSUMÉ APRIL 12, 2020

Publications

Study of Load Balancing Approaches in Distributed Computing Environment

Thesis

AUTHOR, JAYPEE INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY UNIVERSITY

June 2015

• Comparitive study of load balancing approaches for distributed environments.

An efficient technique to control road traffic using Fuzzy Neural Network System

Research Paper

AUTHOR, JAYPEE INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY UNIVERSITY

October 2014

• IEEE Journal - Xplore Digital Library Link

Projects

Deloitte Consulting **Enterprise HR Portal**

JAVA, MICRO-SERVICES, SPRING BOOT, HIBERNATE, SQL, REST APIS, GIT, GERRIT, JIRA, SPRINT PLANNING

2018 - 2019

- · Responsible for development of HR Portal for a major industry leader in Telecom, Networks and Silicon Chips manufacturing. Delivered a set of 10 Spring Boot modules comprising of 700+ REST Services.
- · Purpose of the Spring Boot modules include capturing employees data from Workday, determining annual bonus, career progressions, annual equity distribution, on-boarding entities from mergers and acquisitions, and reduction management.

Enterprise Customer Support Portal

Deloitte Consulting

JAVA, MICRO-SERVICES, SPRING BOOT, REST APIS, GIT, GERRIT, JIRA

2018

· Responsible for solo end-to-end delivery of a back-end only Spring Boot module comprising of 15 REST APIs for administrative and executive operations such as granting permission to manage and access software and documents to users.

Enterprise M2M Data Services Platform

2017

JAVA, SPRING BOOT, SHELL SCRIPTING, JUNIT, POWER MOCKITO, ZOOKEEPER, NAGIOS, DEVOPS

- Responsible for solo end-to-end delivery of a back-end only Spring Boot based system downtime management module using JMX operations and maintenance mode.
- · Responsible for modernization and DevOps of legacy web apps to modern Spring Boot based modules.

Study of load balancing approaches in distributed computing environment

P.G., J.I.I.T. Noida

· Study based on survey, comparison and analysis of performance of various load balancing approaches in distributed computing environment.

Intelligent Traffic Control - Decision Support System

U.G., J.I.I.T. Noida

JAVA, MACHINE LEARNING, NEURAL NETWORKS

2013

· Proposed, implemented and validated a novel technique to control road traffic using a pre-trained Fuzzy Neural Network Tool.

Web Proxy Server U.G., J.I.I.T. Noida

PYTHON, COMPUTER NETWORKS

· Implemented a Python based Proxy Server for caching, filtering and blocking web requests and data elements.

Rewards & Recognition

Jul. 2019 Applause Award, Technical contribution and work ethic during a critical project Deloitte USI

Feb. 2019 Applause Award, Project delivery excellence Deloitte USI

Jan. 2019 **Spot Award**, Operational excellence during project go live Deloitte USI Dec. 2018 Applause Award, Excellent performance and ownership Deloitte USI

Sep. 2017 Apex Award, Unsupervised delivery and individual contribution to project

Languages _

English Fluent - Mastery level in English listening and speaking skills Versant Test - Pearson Education

Hindi Native